<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-07T01:24:41-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wedge Head Skunk</title><subtitle>A newsletter about food and technology</subtitle><author><name>Jim Partee</name></author><entry><title type="html">How do Delivery Apps like Instacart and Uber Eats Know Which Items are In-Stock at Nearby Grocery and Convenience Stores?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/2023/05/04/INF.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How do Delivery Apps like Instacart and Uber Eats Know Which Items are In-Stock at Nearby Grocery and Convenience Stores?" /><published>2023-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/2023/05/04/INF</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/2023/05/04/INF.html"><![CDATA[<p>As the pandemic changed the way we shop for groceries and essentials, many of us turned to delivery apps like Instacart and Uber Eats to get our daily needs delivered straight to our doorstep. These companies had to develop methods for indexing the available products at a wider variety of stores than previously, and in doing so, had to solve some very interesting challenges to the customer experience.</p>

<p>Using the massive increase in revenues, these delivery apps invested millions in the ability to index and merchandise menus to be easily accessible to consumers.  However, a frustrating experience that can still persist is selecting an item on the app only to receive a message that says "Item not found" (INF).</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">INFs and the Customer Experience</h2>

<p>INFs are a source of disappointment for customers, who often do not get what they want or end up with unsatisfactory substitutes. This has prompted delivery apps to find innovative ways to prevent these occurrences and improve their overall service.</p>

<p>One way delivery apps are preventing INFs is by gathering ground truth information in innovative ways. For example, Uber Eats pays drivers a small bonus to take pictures of shelves to understand inventory levels and item availability in real time. Additionally, some services have started to pipe in consumer data to provide real-time inventory levels for specific stores. These approaches help align customer expectations about the frequency of INFs and improve overall customer satisfaction.</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">How Delivery Apps should Manage INFs</h2>
<a href='https://postimages.org/' target='_blank'><img src='https://i.postimg.cc/ZKjZhfj8/07.png' style="display:block; margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto" class="img" alt='07'/></a>
<span class="caption text-muted">One strategy to align customer expectations with the possibility of an INF - adding banners to items that may be low in stock. (Source: Albertson’s via DoorDash)</span>

<p>However, even with these innovative methods, INFs can still occur. Delivery apps should employ a three-pronged approach to address this frustrating customer experience because it is inevitable sometimes. First, they ought to make it easy for customers to share their substitution preferences.  They should strive to understand their level of flexibility and intent beyond just a list of SKUs. Most apps allow for a pre-selected group of substitutions to be chosen before or directly after ordering.  But pre-selecting a group of potential substitutes may not fully understand the use case behind why the customer ordered. For example, let's say you order acetaminophen in liquid form from your local bodega, but they only have NyQuil.  If you get substituted for NyQuil, but the purpose behind the order was to acquire medicine for your morning routine, that may not be suitable.</p>

<p>Second, they ought to improve the process for customers and drivers to communicate about solutions when substitutions are needed.  If the customer chooses not to pre-select substitutes or the selected options aren’t available, the shopper and customer need to be able to briefly discuss what the best option is— usually some other item or a refund.  Most apps have solved this by providing in-app messaging.  Some high-performing Instacart shoppers </p>

<p>Third, delivery apps ought to empower drivers to make reasonable decisions that they believe the customer would have made in the store.  When all else fails, it’s important that the final decisions are made with the customer in mind.  Delivery apps measure INFs from different drivers and rank those highly who deliver amazing customer experiences even through difficulty.  Applications such as DoorDash and Instacart use this data to determine which shoppers should receive the most valuable orders.  </p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Partee</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the pandemic changed the way we shop for groceries and essentials, many of us turned to delivery apps like Instacart and Uber Eats to get our daily needs delivered straight to our doorstep. These companies had to develop methods for indexing the available products at a wider variety of stores than previously, and in doing so, had to solve some very interesting challenges to the customer experience.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Template Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/2020/01/26/dinosaurs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Template Post" /><published>2020-01-26T21:45:13-06:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T21:45:13-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/2020/01/26/dinosaurs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jimpartee-blog/2020/01/26/dinosaurs.html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="section-heading">The Final Frontier</h2>

<p>There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.</p>

<p>There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.</p>

<blockquote class="blockquote">The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.</blockquote>

<p>Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">Reaching for the Stars</h2>

<p>As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450" alt="Demo Image">
<span class="caption text-muted">To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.</span>

<p>Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.</p>

<p>As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.</p>

<p>Placeholder text by <a href="http://spaceipsum.com/">Space Ipsum</a>. Photographs by <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Partee</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Final Frontier]]></summary></entry></feed>